A woman’s past unlocks the truth buried within her soul.
Mrs. Dalloway is a drama, romance film directed by Marleen Gorris.
Clarissa Dalloway looks back on her youth as she
readies for a gathering at her house.
The wife of a legislator and a doyenne of London's upper-crust party scene, Clarissa finds that the plight
of ailing war veteran Septimus Warren Smith reminds her of a past romance with Peter Walsh.
In flashbacks, young Clarissa explores her possibilities with Peter.
Mrs. Clarissa Dalloway, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Young Clarissa, played by Natascha McElhone.
Peter Walsh, played by Michael Kitchen.
Young Peter, played by Alan Cox.
Lady Rosseter, played by Sarah Badel.
Young Sally, played by Lena Headey.
Mrs Dalloway is a 1997 British drama film, a co-production by the United Kingdom, the United States, and the
Netherlands, directed by Marleen Gorris and starring Vanessa Redgrave, Natascha McElhone and Michael Kitchen.
Based on the 1925 novel by Virginia Woolf, and moving continually between the present and the past that is in the
characters' heads, it covers a day in the life of Mrs Dalloway, whose husband is a prosperous politician in London.
The film explores themes of woman director,
emotional instability, emotional journey.
The tone is emotional.